{
    "id": "77c451c4e9a4457d9592d7b10cb4e578",
    "title": "Continuous Tenses Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "e769e252eba94b529d72a43fa65c58b7",
            "title": "Continuous Tenses Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "I …………………….. an interesting novel now.",
                    "description": "We use the present continuous here because the time expression now gives the indication that we are talking about the present.",
                    "answers": [
                        "was reading",
                        "am reading",
                        "will be reading"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "She ………………………. with her parents at the moment.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "was staying",
                        "is staying",
                        "will be staying"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "This time tomorrow we ………………………. Raj’s birthday.",
                    "description": "We use the future continuous here because we are talking about an action or situation that will be in progress at a particular point of time in future.",
                    "answers": [
                        "were celebrating",
                        "are celebrating",
                        "will be celebrating"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "The child ………………………… for his parents.",
                    "description": "There is no time reference here hence the present continuous is used.",
                    "answers": [
                        "was waiting",
                        "is waiting",
                        "will be waiting"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ……………………… ready when she came.",
                    "description": "The past tense in the subordinate clause clearly indicates that we are talking about past time.",
                    "answers": [
                        "was getting",
                        "am getting",
                        "will be getting"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "He ………………………… in the afternoon.",
                    "description": "The present continuous can be used to talk about future events if the arrangement already exists. The future continuous is also possible here.",
                    "answers": [
                        "was leaving",
                        "is leaving",
                        "will be leaving"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "The child …………………….. soundly.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "was sleeping",
                        "is sleeping",
                        "will be sleeping"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ……………………… when the lights went out.",
                    "description": "The past tense in the subordinate clause clearly indicates that we are talking about past time.",
                    "answers": [
                        "was reading",
                        "am reading",
                        "will be reading"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "The boys ………………………. in the park when it started raining.",
                    "description": "The past tense in the subordinate clause clearly indicates that we are talking about past time.",
                    "answers": [
                        "were playing",
                        "was playing",
                        "are playing"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "We …………………… to Mexico next summer.",
                    "description": "The present continuous can be used to talk about future events if the arrangement already exists. The future continuous is also possible here.",
                    "answers": [
                        "were going",
                        "are going",
                        "will be going"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "The car …………………… for a service next week.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "is going in",
                        "was going in",
                        "has going in"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Don’t phone them now – they ……………………. dinner.",
                    "description": "The future continuous is often used to predict the present. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "were having",
                        "are having",
                        "will be having"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}